<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recursion on David Raab</title>
    <link>https://davidraab.github.io/tags/recursion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recursion on David Raab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidraab.github.io/tags/recursion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Function Application and Composition</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/function-application-and-composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/function-application-and-composition/</guid>
      <description>Function application is probably one of those terms in functional programming that sounds more scarier as the topic really is. The idea behind functional application just means that we execute a function to get the result. Let&amp;rsquo;s take the example of calculating the square root of 2.0. We can write the following in F# to do that:&#xA;1 let x = sqrt 2.0 The interesting part is how we read this example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catamorphisms</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/catamorphisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/catamorphisms/</guid>
      <description>Up to this point I created various articles about fold, in my Series I also created a category named Fold (Catamorphisms) but up till now I didn&amp;rsquo;t explained how this articles related to each other, or what Catamorphisms mean. In this article I want to talk about the remaining parts.&#xA;The List Catamorphisms is a generalization that emerged from the list data-structure. The list data-structure, how it is found in functional programming, is usually build as a single linked list.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPS fold -- fold with early exit</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/cps-fold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/cps-fold/</guid>
      <description>The most general function to traverse a data-structures is the fold function. But fold has one problem that is sometimes not optimal. It always traverses the whole data-structure and we cannot abort the recusion early.&#xA;But sometimes, that is exactly what we want to do. For example when we want to search for a specific element in a list, when we found it, we don&amp;rsquo;t want to go through the remaing list.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuations and foldBack</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/continuations-and-foldback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/continuations-and-foldback/</guid>
      <description>In From mutable loops to immutable folds we implemented foldBack through rev and fold. In this post I show you how you can implement foldBack by using a continuation function.&#xA;Functions Before we see how to implement foldBack, I want to give you analogy first. This analogy helped me in a lot of cases. I hope that this analogy will also help you in better understanding the further post, or probably even in other areas in programming in general.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From mutable loops to immutable folds</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/loops-to-folds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/loops-to-folds/</guid>
      <description>When we ask of key-features of functional programming, you will probably hear two things most often. Immutability and recursion. But why is that so? As Immutability also becomes more important in OO languages you will probably find a lot of reason for that one, but why are recursive functions so important? The short answer is, because of Immutability! To understand the connection between those, let&amp;rsquo;s start with some code that uses loops with mutation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
