<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on David Raab</title>
    <link>https://davidraab.github.io/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on David Raab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidraab.github.io/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Example: F# List is Anemic</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/example-f-list-is-anemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/example-f-list-is-anemic/</guid>
      <description>In my previous article Anemic Domain Model: Data and behaviour should be separated I explain why you should stick to an Anemic Domain Model and which benefits it offers.&#xA;In this article we look into F# to see how it applies there. F# has many built-in data-structures like many languages. One of the most used data-structure is the List data-structure.&#xA;When you follow a typical object-oriented solution then maybe you would end up with a List class, maybe you will consider some data as private, because the way how to manage a list should be managed by the class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why map was not discovered in Object-Oriented Programming</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/why-map-was-not-discovered-in-object-oriented-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/why-map-was-not-discovered-in-object-oriented-programming/</guid>
      <description>When I started Perl programming back around 2003 one thing that Perl had, what most language didn&amp;rsquo;t, was the existence of the map function.&#xA;In today world of programming from JavaScript, C#, Java and so on, the concept nowadays is so common that nearly every language has it, and usually every programmers understands and use it.&#xA;That was not always the case. I can remember when LINQ was introduced in C# how a lot of people was complaining how from know on C# would be a language that nobody else never can read or understand anymore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anemic Domain Model: Data and Behaviour should be separated</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/anemic-domain-model-data-and-behaviour-should-be-separated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/anemic-domain-model-data-and-behaviour-should-be-separated/</guid>
      <description>In the object-oriented world there is often a debate around the so called Anemic Domain Model. An Anemic Domain Model is when you clearly separate your data and your code.&#xA;In object-orientation this is usually considered bad, but when you look at procedural or functional-programming things change. They are seen as good practice you should follow. So who is right?&#xA;Rich Domain Model The opposite of an Anemic Domain Model is usually called a Rich Domain Model the idea of it goes as follow.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
