<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>oop on David Raab</title>
    <link>https://davidraab.github.io/tags/oop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in oop on David Raab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidraab.github.io/tags/oop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Functional Programming</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/introduction-to-functional-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/introduction-to-functional-programming/</guid>
      <description>In this article I want to give a general introduction to some of the fundamental ideas of functional programming. I just start with the idea of function as data, and explain why functions are viewed as data and why it makes sense to pass functions as arguments.
When we understand this concept, I start explaining lambda expression, currying, partial application and closures. All of this ideas built on each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Immutability and Pure Functions (for OOP)</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/immutability-and-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/immutability-and-functions/</guid>
      <description>One important concept in functional programming is immutability. But also in object-oriented programming immutability and so called immutable objects getting more attention. The problem that I see especially from object-oriented programmers are really bad explanations. A lot of explanation I had see described it like this: Just create a class and make all fields readonly (final or const) and you have an immutable object.
Explanations like these are horrible. Such explanations are so simplified that I would even call them wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
