<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oop on David Raab</title>
    <link>https://davidraab.github.io/tags/oop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oop on David Raab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidraab.github.io/tags/oop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>interfaces in functional programming</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/interfaces-in-functional-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/interfaces-in-functional-programming/</guid>
      <description>Recently I worked with Raylib a graphics library for doing/learning game development. When I created multiple small demos there was one thing I wanted todo across multiple projects. I wanted to drag game objects on the screen. I already solved that problem once so now I just needed to create a general function that allowed me to drag any kind of object, instead of writing a specific solution again and again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>interfaces in functional programming</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/interfaces-in-functional-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/interfaces-in-functional-programming/</guid>
      <description>Recently I worked with Raylib a graphics library for doing/learning game development. When I created multiple small demos there was one thing I wanted todo across multiple projects. I wanted to drag game objects on the screen. I already solved that problem once so now I just needed to create a general function that allowed me to drag any kind of object, instead of writing a specific solution again and again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OOP is Partial Application</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/oop-is-partial-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/oop-is-partial-application/</guid>
      <description>In the past I spent a lot of time in different online forums, websites and so on. As I am interested in general about language design and learnt a lot of languages I also had many discussions with different programmers of different knowledge.&#xA;As I started programming with QBasic and C I am also used to procedural programming. The same goes for Perl. As of Perl 5 (1994) it also contains object-oriented programming, but still some parts of it are procedural.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Class vs Hash</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/class-vs-hash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/class-vs-hash/</guid>
      <description>In my previous articles about object-orientation I explained how OO in general works. I used Perl for the explanation, as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hide its itnernals like most other languages do. That&amp;rsquo;s Why I like Perl&amp;rsquo;s OO.&#xA;Usually OO works that we define a mutable data-structure and pass it to a function that mutates it. So in some sense calling func($obj, $arg1) is the same as $obj-&amp;gt;func($arg1). It&amp;rsquo;s just a different syntax and order we write, but the concept is the same.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Like Perl&#39;s OO</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/why-i-like-perls-oo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/why-i-like-perls-oo/</guid>
      <description>I started programming with QBasic and later C. While it was difficult to learn those languages back then (with no internet and just some books) nothing felt &amp;ldquo;out of place&amp;rdquo; for me.&#xA;For example, when I learned about arrays the first time, it took some time to learn the concept of it, that it is a storage of multiple elements one after another. How it is used and what you can do with it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insanity of Object-Oriented Programming</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/insanity-of-oo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/insanity-of-oo/</guid>
      <description>The insanity of Object-Oriented Programming I started programming back in the 1990s. My first language I learned was QBasic and after 2 days of learning it, i switched to C. Back in these days there was no Internet. Okay, it existed but was not so common as today. Most people still didn&amp;rsquo;t even had computers.&#xA;I picked and learned C because when you got to the programming section in a store it was full of C books.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Object-Oriented Programming in C</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/object-oriented-programming-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/object-oriented-programming-in-c/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s do object-oriented programming in C. First of I am creating an easy example for an Vector2 type. To define a Vector2 in C we use a struct.&#xA;1 2 3 4 struct Vector2 { int X; int Y; }; When you know C#, you are already familiar with a struct. A struct is a value-type in C. It always gets copied as a whole. In C# we have a class that is a reference-type but this doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist in C.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Immutability and Pure Functions (for OOP)</title>
      <link>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/immutability-and-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidraab.github.io/posts/immutability-and-functions/</guid>
      <description>One important concept in functional programming is immutability. But also in object-oriented programming immutability and so called immutable objects getting more attention. The problem that I see especially from object-oriented programmers are really bad explanations. A lot of explanation I had see described it like this: Just create a class and make all fields readonly (final or const) and you have an immutable object.&#xA;Explanations like these are horrible. Such explanations are so simplified that I would even call them wrong.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
